Julia Pasquarella

jpasq93@gmail.com ■ Austin, Texas ■ (210) 548-6822 ■ linkedin.com/in/julialpasquarella/ ■ juliapasquarella.com

Enthusiastic marketing and design professional who specializes in digital marketing and visual communications. Delivers value to the organization by transforming complex ideas into compelling visual narratives that strengthen brand identity. Cultivates high quality engagements that support B2B and B2C sales efforts through planning and executing cross-platform content, event, and product marketing campaigns.

Experience

Enthought, Austin, Tx

Marketing Manager

March 2021-January 2022

- Managed the end-to-end process of digital and event marketing campaigns that generated leads and increased brand awareness for Enthought's materials science & chemistry, semiconductor, and life sciences industry verticals, and their technical training business.
- Led the creation and execution of unique go-to-market strategies for the launch of 3 new training programs;
 designed and optimized landing pages for each program, which resulted in a 15% increase in web traffic in 4 months.
- Developed and designed presentations that supported the growth and retention efforts of several multi-million dollar digital transformation accounts. Collaborated with c-suite and business unit heads on branding and messaging; translated key concepts and value propositions into simple and compelling visuals.

Marketing and Operations Specialist, Training Team

June 2016-March 2021

- Executed multi-channel B2C marketing campaigns that generated leads for Enthought's training programs.
 Analyzed campaign results and delivered reports to key stakeholders.
- Coordinated the creation and design of a facilitation guide for initiating engagements with new digital transformation clients. Provided a standard process that ensured client success and retention.
- Pivoted in-person training programs to a virtual format during the pandemic, exceeding forecasted sales by 20%.
- Improved purchasing experience of Enthought's training programs by implementing, customizing and maintaining a Shopify e-commerce site.
- Re-designed customer satisfaction surveys and streamlined reporting formats and processes that lead to a 40% increase in survey submissions.
- Coordinated over 100 in-person and virtual training programs for global attendees. Enhanced training operations
 and logistics by standardizing processes and authoring clear documentation.

The Construction Industry Institute, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX

Student Graphic Designer

February 2016-June 2017

- Re-designed the layout, figures, and cover of a best practices book.
- Designed covers for 15 research summary booklets.
- Re-designed several customer-facing online training courses.

Digital Media Institute, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX

Student Graphic Designer

June 2012-May 2015

- Contributed to the overall concept, UI/UX design, and Graphic design of a simulation style educational video game that promoted high-level decision-making skills in environmental science, economics, public policy, and political science in high school aged students.
- Worked on the instructional, UI and graphic design of several e-learning modules for UT Math and Biology departments.
- Designed and created 2D and 3D visual assets.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin, Austin TX

2011-2017

BS Biology: Ecology Evolution and Behavior

Bridging Disciplines Program: Digital Arts and Media Certificate

Freshman Research Initiative Program

Volunteer

SciPy 2019 Conference

Activities committee Co-Chair

SciPy 2018 Conference

Activities Committee Member

Skills

Digital Marketing

Email Marketing

Social Media Marketing

Content Marketing

Graphic Design

Interaction Design

Salesforce

MailChimp

WordPress

Adobe Creative Suite

Google Analytics

Shopify

Zapier

HTML

Python